Pedro Brandimarte

Résumé

Background in computational and theoretical physics, and mathematics. I carry extensive experience in software development, with a deep knowledge on algorithms, abstract data structures, hybrid parallel programming and high-performance computing. I am fascinated by the changes of paradigm that machine learning algorithms pose against traditional programming, as well as new forms of computing such as quantum computing. I am always very enthusiastic about tackling problems out of my comfort zone and working in a cooperative environment.

Areas of Expertise

Programming languages

Advanced Python, C++, C, Fortran, shell script

Intermediate R, OCTAVE/MATLAB

Basic JAVA, RUBY, LUA

Operating systems

Linux, Windows and MacOS

Key competencies

- o Research, Computational Physics, Mathematical Modeling, Data Analysis
- Probability Theory, Statistics, Linear Algebra
- Algorithms, Abstract Data Structures, Parallel Computing, HPC
- Machine Learning Techniques, Deep Learning, Data Science, Data Analytics
- Communication Skills, Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Teaching/Training Skills, Goal-Oriented

Open source codes

- 1 Contributor of Auto Kernel Generator **AKG** (gitee.com/mindspore/akg/tree/master), a polyhedral based optimizer and code generator for operators in deep neural networks. Part of the **MindSpore** project (www.mindspore.cn/en), an open source all scenario deep learning computing framework. [Python, C++]
- 2 **MCMCneuro** (github.com/brandimarte/MCMCneuro) data driven graph model for neuronal interactions using Bayesian statistics and Markov Chain Monte Carlo. [C, SHELL, R]
- 3 Contributor of **SIESTA/TranSIESTA** codes (departments.icmab.es/leem/siesta) for ab initio electronic structure and transport simulations. [FORTRAN, MPI, OPENMP]
- 4 **KPM** (github.com/brandimarte/kpm) kernel polynomial method implementation using Chebyshev expansion for disordered lattices. [FORTRAN95, MPI]
- 5 **PhOnonS ITeratIVE VIBRATIONS** (github.com/brandimarte/vibrations) for vibrational and electron-phonon coupling analysis via first-principles. [C, SHELL]
- 6 Inelastic Disorder (github.com/brandimarte/idisorder) for transport on devices with random defects and inelastic scattering. [FORTRAN95, C++, MPI, CUDA]
- 7 Inelastic SMEAGOL (bitbucket.org/brandimarte/smeagol-2.0 request access) for ab initio inelastic electronic transport of atomic scale devices. [FORTRAN95, MPI, OPENMP]

1 1/2

Pedro Brandimarte Résumé

Work Experience

2021-present Huawei Technologies, France

Parallel computing / Accelerator programming research engineer at Paris Research Center.

2020–2021 Alerion Tec, Spain

Software engineer on computer vision, parallel imaging processing, autonomous localization and mapping.

Postdoctoral researcher

2017–2020 Donostia International Physics Center - DIPC, Spain

Electronic structure and quantum transport in graphene-based nanostructures and networks.

funding: DIPC Foundation

2015-2017 Centro de Física de Materiales - CFM, Spain

Development of tools and theoretical models for studying electron transport in nanoscale devices.

funding: European Commission, 7o Framework Programme, ICT Collaborative project

Scientific training

2006–2007 CERN - European Organization for Nuclear Research, Switzerland, ALICE experiment

Development on the AliRoot framework for simulation at the ALICE Off-line group (950h).

funding: European Commission, programme América Latina - Formación Académica (ALFA)

2004–2005 **Universidade de São Paulo**, *Brazil*, Coherent Manipulation of Atoms and Light Laboratory Development of a magneto-optical trap experiment.

funding: National Council of Technological and Scientific Development (CNPq/PIBIC)

Supervision

2019 Donostia International Physics Center - DIPC, Spain, Supervisor

Electronic properties and tight-binding parametrization of twisted bi-layer graphene.

student: Itsaso Blanco, University College London, Faculty of Maths and Physical Sciences.

2018 Donostia International Physics Center - DIPC, Spain, Supervisor

Code development for evaluating bond order of graphene-based structures via graph theory.

student: Amaia Juaristi Arrizabalaga, Universidad del País Vasco, Departamento de Matemáticas.

Teaching

2008 Educafro, Cohab de Taipas and Cohab Brasilândia

Teacher of physics and mathematics (volunteer).

2004–2005 Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil, Instructor

Experimental Physics III and IV.

Education

2008–2014 Ph.D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo, USP, Brazil

Study of the influence of localized vibrational modes in charge transport properties at nanoscale systems.

2002–2007 Bachelor in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo, USP, Brazil

Complementary education

2009–2014 **Bachelor in Applied and Computational Mathematics**, *Universidade de São Paulo*, USP, Brazil Concluded 65% of the courses (1350h).

Languages

Portuguese Mother Tongue

English Fluent Understand well, speak well, read well, write well

Spanish Advanced Understand well, speak well, read well, write well

French Intermediate Understand well, speak reasonably, read well, write reasonably

Scientific Production

Author of 17 publications in high-quality peer-reviewed journals, 11 as first theory author, with average impact factor 8.64 and all in Q1 (citation metrics at scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user =P-rSYmoAAAAJ). Reviewer of scientific journals, including *ChemistrySelect*, *Physica Status Solidi*, *The Journal of Physical Chemistry*, *Journal of Physics*. *Condensed Matter*, and *The European Physical Journal*. Attended and presented work in scientific conferences/workshops worldwide (Germany, Hong Kong, USA, Spain, Denmark, Austria and Brazil), whose complete list can be found at lattes.cnpq.br/8885012919924529.

2 2/2